Guide to the Stuart Saunders Smith papers ARCH174
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
- Recordings, 1970-2018; II
  - Recordings of Smith and his works, 1970-2018
    - Angels: Mvts. II-III; Rough Recording, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - As If; Jessyca rough edit, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Big Falls, Little Falls, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Carrie Rose, flute; Stuart Saunders Smith: Rose, Robert Erickson: High Flyer, undated; 1 Compact Discs DVD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Castine, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Closing (on Track 8), undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Dad's Time Had Come (multiple mixes), undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Drew Krausse: Performances, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Echo (excerpt demo), undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Echo, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Far Away (Mvt. I), undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Hawk: The Saxophone Music of Stuart Saunders Smith, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
      CD removed from correspondance from Mark Engebretson dated 2011-09-14.
    - Home of the Brave, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Husbands and Wives and One for Two, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - In 25: Stuart Saunders Smith 25-Year-Retrospective, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Just Seven and Jared Steward Senior Recital, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Language; Rough Mix 1, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Lazarus; Pre-Master No Reverb, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Links 1-7, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Links 8-11, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - New England; Berndt Thurner, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - On: Empty and Quilt, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Palm Sunday; Excerpts, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Plenty; Test Recordings, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Reflect; Alaina and Brian Glazer, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Remember and Crossings; Jude Traxler, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Return and Recall, circus version; CCM, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Seed Savers, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD; Hybrid Disc Audio Demo and PDF Score. (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - "Solo Flute Piece"; Prof. Gisela Mashayekhi, flute, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Smith "Copy(?)"; finalized, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Stuart [illegible], undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Stuart Sampler, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - They Looked Like Strangers; Studio Recording, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Things That Grow Smaller, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Three Winter Carols; performed by Trevor Saint, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Tim Broscious Lecture Recital, undated; 1 Compact Discs DVD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Wellspring; Joseph Van Hassel, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - When Music Is Missing, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - When The Body Betrays, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - When The Moment Is Too Big, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Faces by Stuart Smith, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7 inches (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
    - Stu Art Sampler, undated; 1 Reels Sampler Reel 1/4 inch 7 inches (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Recording of Stu Art Sampler, includes Pinetop, performed by Paul Hoffman (piano), Tunnels, Stuart Smith, (vocals), Gifts, Paul Hoffman (piano), Gail Cameron (flute), Wayne Cameron, (trumpet), Two Makes Three.
    - Two Makes Three, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Master recording of Pinetop.
    - Links Stuart Smith, undated; 1 Cassettes VHS T-120 (Box Shared Videotape 1)
      The Links Series of Vibraphone Essays by Stuart Saunders Smith.
    - By Language Embellished, undated; 1 Cassettes VHS T-60 (Box Shared Videotape 1)
      Stuart Smith Opera By Language Embellished.
    - Darin Woodley "And Points North...", undated; 1 Cassettes VHS T-120 (Box Shared Videotape 1)
      Darin Woodley performs Stuart Saunders Smith's "And Points North...".
    - Bassically Bert, undated; 1 Cassettes DAT (Box Shared Cassette Box 1)
    - Memory Bands, 1986; 1 Phonographs LP, Vinyl 12-inch (Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Gageen, undated; 1 Phonographs LP, Vinyl 12-inch (Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Timbral Variations, undated; 1 Phonographs LP, Vinyl 12-inch (Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Folder 4)
    - What an Indeterminate Composer Composes: Music, Sound, and Noise, undated; 2 Reels 1/4 inch audio reel, Parts 1 and 2 10.5 inch (Reel Q-5613, Reel Q-5614)
  - Recordings of others, 1975-2017
    This sub-series contains recorded performances of compositions that were not written by Stuart Saunders Smith. Many of these were acquired via correspondence between Smith and his colleagues and include professionally mixed and released albums, as well as recorded concerts in both audio and video mediums.
    - Nine Variations Ben Johnston Smith copy., 1975 Apr 13; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Ben Johnston Nine Variations Smith copy.
    - Stuart Dempster at VMBC, 1982 Apr 14; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Stuart Dempster at VMBC April 14, 1982.
    - Here The Sounds Go Round/Dedicace, 1982; 1 Phonographs Eva-Tone Sound Sheet 7-inch (Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Dimension for Four, 1987 Apr 10; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Dimension for Four by Ben Johnston. Program included.
    - Christopher Shultis Compositions, 1988-2000; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Huang Ruo's Compositions, circa 1997; 1 Cassettes Audiocassette (Box Shared Cassette Box 1)
    - Six Rooms for flute, vibraphone, and cello Stephen Makofski, 1999; 1 Cassettes Audiocassette (Box Shared Cassette Box 1)
    - Composed Improvisations, 2000; 1 Cassettes Audiocassette (Box Shared Cassette Box 1)
    - Rachel Koblyakov plays Bach-Partita No. 1, 2001 Jul; 1 Cassettes Audiocassette (Box Shared Cassette Box 1)
    - And where you are is where you are not; Erik Lund, circa 2001; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Cordaw Treatise Walleye, circa 2001; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Improvisations One; Harkins, Turetsky, Lechusza, circa 2002; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Solo Flute Piece, circa 2003; 1 Cassettes DAT (Box Shared Cassette Box 1)
    - Will Redman Recent Works, 2003-2006; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Will Redman, circa 2005-2006; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Benjamin Fraley; "King of Denmark"' PASIC, circa 2011; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - The Miracle of Unintelligibility, circa 2011 (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
      [Moved from correspondence series, found with letter from Kevin D. Lewis circa 2011.]
    - Cooman: For The Graduation; Harvard Commencement Choir, circa 2011-Sep; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Aiyun Huang and Friends; Save Percussion Theater, 2012; 1 Compact Discs DVD; 1 Folders Liner notes (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3, Box Correspondence 6, Folder 5)
    - Timber by Michael Gordon; Mantra Percussion, 2012; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - NMNC Gettysburg Excerpts; Stephen Miles, circa 2012; 1 Compact Discs DVD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Cooman: The Evening Choir; Harvard University Choir, 2012; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Ebow Demo, circa 2013 Jun; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Xtensions; Ron Coulter, 2016; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Ubiquity; Bob McCormick, 2016; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Origins Concert Series, 2016 Mar 05; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Origins Concert Series, 2016 Apr 23; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Web Passage by Carrie Rose; Ellen Klimans, soprano; Carrie Rose, flute, 2016 Jul; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Origins Concert Series, 2016 Nov 05; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Poulenc: La Voix Humaine (opening night); Hillary Jean Young, soprano; Kyle Adam Blair, piano, 2017 May 10; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Untitled Concert Smith Copy, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Smith copy Track List: 1.Five Fragments,2.Knocking Piece (1962),3.Concerto for Brass.
    - Ben Johnston Crossings Smith Copy, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Ben Johnston Crossings Smith copy Track List: 3.Vergings The Silence and 4.Ascent.
    - Ben Johnston The Demon Lover's Doubles, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Ben Johnston The Demon Lover's Doubles Smith copy.
    - Ben Johnston Duo (2 violins), undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 5-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Ben Johnston Duo for Two Violins.
    - Ben Johnston Knocking Piece, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 5-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Ben Johnston Knocking Piece.
    - Knocking Piece, Five Fragments, Ci-Git Satie, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Track List: 1. Knocking Piece (1962), 2. Five Fragments (1961), 3. Ci-Git-Satie, for 8 Singers, drums, and bass (1966).
    - Ben Johnston Smith Copy Night and Gambit, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Ben Johnston Smith copy Track List: 1.Night (Cantata) 2.Gambit.
    - Ben Johnston Smith copy, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Ben Johnston Smith copy Track List: 1.Sea Dirge 2.Knocking Piece.
    - Ben Johnston Smith copy, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Ben Johnston Smith copy Track List: 1.Septet 2.Songs of Innocence.
    - Ben Johnston Smith copy St. Joan Suite for Piano, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Ben Johnston Smith copy St. Joan, Suite for Piano.
    - Coleman: Quodlibet on a theme by Claude Bolling, undated; 1 Reels Master 1/4 inch 7-inch (Box Shared Audio Reels 1)
      Quodlibet on a theme by Claude Bolling by Randolph Coleman. Robert Shannon (piano), Mark Bernat (bass), Douglas Walter (percussion).
    - Johnston, undated; 1 Cassettes Audiocassette (Box Shared Cassette Box 1)
    - Johnston-Crossings, undated; 1 Cassettes Audiocassette (Box Shared Cassette Box 1)
    - Bill Evans/Jim Hall; Boaz Rubens/Kyle Blair, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Let's Cathect; Colin Holter, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Morton Feldman '80; #2 Good, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Senior Recital, undated; 2 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 Compact Discs CD (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3)
- Correspondence, 1975-2018; undated; III
  This series primarily contains correspondence received by Stuart Saunders Smith, as well as some copies and drafts of letters he has sent. Many of the letters within this series are professional correspondences from colleagues regarding performances of his compositions and the commissioning of new compositions. There are also several letters from his family throughout his life. Some entries of note include correspondence with Brian Ferneyhough, letters from Berndt Thurner in which they discuss the preparations for a tour in Vienna that would feature Smith's works, and early correspondence between Smith and John Cage.
  The series is in chronological order.
  - 1975-1999 (Box Correspondence 1)
  - 2000-2004 (Box Correspondence 2)
  - 2005-2011 (Box Correspondence 3)
  - 2012-2014 (Box Correspondence 4)
  - 2015-2018 (Box Correspondence 5)
  - Undated (Box Correspondence 6, Folder 1)
- Writings, 1974-2018; undated; IV
  This series consists of both published and unpublished writings either written and/or edited by Stuart Saunders Smith, or obtained by Smith from his colleagues and friends.
  The series is arranged into two sub-series: a. Writings by Stuart Saunders Smith and b. Writings by Others.
  - Writings by Stuart Saunders Smith, 1975-2008; undated
    This sub-series contains a wide variety of writings, both scholarly and personal, authored or edited by Stuart Saunders Smith. Smith's published writings range from treatises on graphic notation, percussion, and the nature of music itself, to an interview with John Cage. The series also includes Smith's poetry, which he has written throughout his life, including periodicals that feature his works, as well as poems from his youth bound in delicate notebooks. Other personal writings include memo notebooks, loose leaf manuscripts of program notes, journal articles, and poems (or as he refers to them, "speech songs").
    This sub-series is arranged chronologically.
    - Handwritten Notebooks, 1975-1977, undated (Box Writings 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Sonic Specificity in Ideographic Notation, 1976 (Box Writings 1, Folder 3)
    - Percussionist, 1978-1979 (Box Writings 1, Folder 4)
    - Perspectives of New Music reprints, 1979-1998 (Box Writings 1, Folder 5)
    - Scenarios; "Return and recall" and "Initiatives and Reactions", 1980 (Box Writings 1, Folder 6)
    - Scores: An Anthology of New Music, 1981 (Box Writings 1, Folder 7)
    - Percussive Notes, 1981-2005 (Box Writings 1, Folder 8)
    - Percussive Notes Research Edition Reprint, 1983 (Box Writings 1, Folder 9)
    - Percussion in Discussion, 1984 (Box Writings 1, Folder 10)
    - The Pearl, 1986; 1990 (Box Shared Book Tray 3)
    - Handwritten Writings, 1986, undated (Box Writings 1, Folder 11)
    - Words and Spaces: An Anthology of Twentieth Century Musical Experiments in Language and Sonic Environments, 1989 (Box Shared Book Tray 3)
    - Notes for 20th Century Music Scores, circa 1989 (Box Writings 1, Folder 12)
    - Twentieth Century Music Scores, 1989 (Box Writings 1, Folder 13)
    - Writings about John Cage, 1993 (Box Writings 1, Folder 14)
    - Herbert Brun: Towards Composition, 1998 Mar 12 (Box Writings 1, Folder 15)
    - Ex Tempore, 2008 (Box Large Shared Book Tray 1)
    - Action Music, undated (Box Writings 1, Folder 16)
    - Adolescent Poetry, undated (Box Writings 1, Folder 17)
    - Being Composed by the Snare Drum, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 1)
    - A Composer's Mosaic, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 2)
    - Sections of Composing, Thoughts, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 3)
    - Forming the Open Universe, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 4)
    - The Geography of Time on Interpretation, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 5)
    - Graphic Scores: Musical Notation as Visual Art, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 6)
    - A Music of Co-Existence, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 7)
    - Renewal, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 8)
    - Stuart's Self-Interview, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 9)
    - Thinking On Tools Touching My Trade, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 10)
    - A Vocabulary In Time, undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 11)
    - Writing Degree Zero (Notecards), undated (Box Writings 2, Folder 12)
    - Personal Memo Books, undated (Box Writings 4)
  - Writings by Others, 1974-2018; undated
    This sub-series features many scholarly articles and dissertations written by others regarding Smith and his compositions. These include published periodicals as well as books. There are also publications and other writings he acquired via correspondence and friendship (some of which include personal inscriptions) that do not reference him or his work.
    - Writings about Music, by Steve Reich, 1974-1975 (Box Writings 2, Folder 13)
    - Bob Gregson 1975 Catalog (Box Writings 2, Folder 14)
    - Interface, 1984 (Box Writings 2, Folder 15)
    - Percussive Notes Research Edition, 1984 (Box Writings 2, Folder 16)
    - Andrew Hudson: A Glimpse Behind The Canvas, 1986 (Box Writings 2, Folder 17)
    - Grand River Suite by Robie Liscomb, 1986 (Box Writings 2, Folder 18)
    - New Instrumentation and Orchestration: An Outline for Study, by Larry Polansky, 1986; Includes signed inscription by the author. (Box Large Shared Book Tray 1)
    - Karol Szymanowski: An Anthology, 1986 (Box Large Shared Book Tray 1)
    - Journal of New Music Research Reprint, 1994 (Box Writings 2, Folder 19)
    - Percussive Notes, 1996-2018 (Box Writings 2, Folder 20)
    - Bundesrealgymnasium Klagenfurt-Viktring, 1999 (Box Writings 2, Folder 21)
    - Conversation Piece, 2000 (Box Writings 2, Folder 22)
    - Ex Tempore, 2007 (Box Large Shared Book Tray 1)
    - Instrumental Musician, 2008 (Box Writings 2, Folder 23)
    - Interview by Jude Trexler, Circa 2008 (Box Writings 2, Folder 24)
    - Journal of the IAWM, 2008 (Box Writings 2, Folder 25)
    - Perspectives of New Music, 2009 Winter; 2017 Summer (Box Writings 2, Folder 26)
    - Seeing Cage, Hearing Beuys, 2010 (Box Writings 2, Folder 27)
    - Theses and Dissertations, 2011-2017 (Box Writings 3, Folder 1)
    - Winnicott's Potential Space in Music and Dance, 2011-Nov-18 (Box Writings 3, Folder 2)
    - On the Nature of Percussion Masterworks, circa 2012 (Box Writings 3, Folder 3)
    - An Isn't Being An Is: Phenomenologies of Silence in the Music of Stuart Saunders Smith, circa 2013 (Box Writings 3, Folder 4)
    - The Memory of a Previous Now: Between Uttering and Executing, 2015 Sep 26 (Box Writings 3, Folder 5)
    - Interview with Stuart Saunders Smith, 2016 Nov 15 (Box Writings 3, Folder 6)
    - NACWPI Journal, 2016 (Box Writings 3, Folder 7)
    - Grotowski/Brook/Mamet: Theory and Practice for the Actor-Percussionist, by Bill Sallak, Circa 2017 (Box Writings 3, Folder 8)
    - Around the Alamo: The Making of Smith Publications, undated (Box Writings 3, Folder 9)
    - Computer Graphics by Herbert Bruhn, undated (Box Writings 3, Folder 10)
    - Drumset "Changes" in Blue, undated (Box Writings 3, Folder 11)
    - From Musical Ideas to Computers and Back, undated (Box Writings 3, Folder 12)
    - Misc. Selections, undated (Box Writings 3, Folder 13)
    - Notes, undated (Box Writings 3, Folder 14)
    - Playing Polyrhythms on the Guitar; Closing (after Goya), undated (Box Writings 3, Folder 15)
    - Traffic/Light: Post-Cage Discussions on Silence, undated (Box Writings 3, Folder 16)
- Subject Files, 1960-2018; undated; V
  This series contains various personal and professional subject files retained by Stuart Saunders Smith, some as early as his childhood until 2018. The largest portions of the series are the publicity and programs files. Other notable files include the awards, childhood documents, contracts, and royalties files.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by file name.
  - Atlantic Center for the Arts, 2000-2006 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 1)
  - Awards, 1986-2016 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 2-4, Box Compositions 13, Folder 8)
    This file contains the various awards given to Stuart Saunders Smith. Included are his degrees from the University of Hartford, the grants awarded to him from the State of Maryland for his various residencies, and awards from the Percussive Arts Society.
  - Childhood Documents, 1960-1965 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 5)
  - Contracts, 1980-2008 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 6)
  - Hand Drawn Portrait, undated (Box Compositions 13, Folder 12)
  - Maryland State Arts Council, 1997; 2001 (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 7)
  - Programs, 1980-2018; undated (Box Subject Files 1, Folder 8-12, Box Subject Files 2, Folder 1-5)
    This file features many of the various programs that have featured Stuart Saunders Smith's compositions in concerts held around the world. These programs span throughout Smith's life and career. The file features several programs from Smith's doctoral tenure at the University of Illinois, as well as international premieres by world-renowned ensembles and musicians such as So Percussion, Bert Turetzky, Kyle Adam Blair, and Carrie Rose. Many of the aforementioned musicians have been champions of Smith's music and appear multiple times throughout the file. The majority of the programs take place at the University of Maryland, Baltimore County (UMBC) and the University of Akron (Smith was a professor at both), in addition to the surrounding areas for each. Smith's music has also been featured at several musical festivals, most commonly appearing on programs for the Percussive Arts Society's International Convention (PASIC).
  - Publicity, 1965-2018 (Box Subject Files 2, Folder 6-13, Box Compositions 13, Folder 9-11, Box Compositions OV 1, Folder 5-6, Box Correspondence 6, Folder 7)
    This file includes various publicity materials including posters, postcards, and news clippings that advertise, feature, or review Stuart Saunders Smith, his compositions, and the various recordings that feature them. The file includes press clips from Smith's performances as a drummer in his high school jazz band as well as posters advertising world premieres throughout the United States and internationally.
  - Royalties, 1993-2018 (Box Correspondence 6, Folder 8)
- Photographs, Circa 1990-1997; undated; VI
  This series consists of photographs of Stuart Saunders Smith (including portraits, candid, and performance photographs), as well as some personal photographs of Smith's friends and family.
  - Photographs of Stuart Saunders Smith, circa 1990, undated (Box Correspondence 6, Folder 8, Box Writings 4)
    Consists of print photographs of Stuart Saunders Smith, as well as two CDs of digital images of Smith.
  - Performance Photographs, undated (Box Correspondence 6, Folder 9, Box Writings 4)
  - Photos of Family and Friends, 1997, undated (Box Correspondence 6, Folder 10, Box Writings 4)
- Restricted, VII (Box Restricted 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series contains restricted materials. Some files are inaccessible only during the lifetime of Stuart Saunders Smith. Others are permanently restricted and only accessible to Archives' staff (in these cases redacted versions are available to all researchers in other series).
- Duplicates, VIII
  This series contains duplicate copies of materials in the collection.
  - Duplicate Recordings, 1997-2014; 17 Compact Discs CD; 3 Compact Discs DVD; 2 Cassettes Audiocassette; 1 Phonographs LP, Vinyl 12-inch (Box Recordings-CD/DVD Box 3, Box Shared 12 in. Phonograph Record Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Duplicate Publicity Materials (Box Correspondence 6, Folder 11-12)